Coefficient of Restitution; Impulse
Candidates
 should be able to:
(a)
recall and use Newton’s experimental law and the definition of coefficient of restitution, the 
property 
01
e
≤≤
, and the meaning of
 the terms ‘perfectly elastic’ (
1
e
=
) and ‘inelastic’ 
(
0
e
=
); 
(b)
use Newton’s experimental law in the course of solving problems that may be modelled as the 
direct impact of two smooth spheres or as the direct imp
act of a smooth sphere with a fixed 
plane surface;
(c)
recall and use the definition of impulse as change of momentum (in one dimension only, 
restricted to ‘instantaneous’ events, so that calculations involving force and time are not 
included). 