Candidates
 should be able to:
(a)
understand the concept of angular speed for a particle moving in a circle, and use the relation 
vr
ω
=
; 
(b)
understand that the acceleration of a particle moving in a circle with constant speed is directed 
towards the centre of the circle, and use the formulae 
2
r
ω
 and 
2
v
r
; 
(c)
solve problems which can be modelled by the motion of a particle moving in a horizontal circle 
with constant speed. 